Guide to the National Coalition for Haitian Rights Records, 1964-2020, bulk 1982-2004 RL.11314
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Programs and Projects, 1986-2004, undated; bulk 1991-2000; 2; 9 boxes
  While these laws and reforms were being enacted in the US, Haitians kept fleeing the despotic regimes that succeeded the Duvaliers. Thus NCHR's investigating and reporting on human rights conditions, educating the US Congress and the Administration in order to influence policymaking and lawmaking continued apace. In 1988, NCHR extended human rights monitoring to the Dominican Republic and the Bahamas, and initiated a monthly bulletin, Haiti Insight. The human rights reporting was key to providing substantive support to Haitian asylum claims. Over time, the bulletin became required reading for US asylum adjudicators. In 1992, the Haitian military took power through a coup d'état and exiled President Aristide. Shortly afterwards, thousands of Haitians took to the high seas and were intercepted by the US Coast Guard and warehoused in the US naval military base at Guantanamo, Cuba (GTMO). Once again, NCHR was at the forefront of advocating for Haitian asylum-seekers. The official records of the litigation undertaken on behalf of the Haitian refugees will not direct the public's attention to NCHR's key role in this effort, but it was substantial. For strategic and practical reasons, the groups involved in the litigation chose a member organization -- the Haitian Centers Council – as the lead organization because it was headquartered in Brooklyn where NCHR and the Yale Law School filed suit on behalf of the Haitians held in GTMO. By 1994, NCHR had secured the release of about 11,000 Haitian refugees and the right for them to seek asylum on U.S. soil. About 3 years later, NCHR secured legislation granting them and thousands of others (an estimated 50,000) legal permanent residence (green cards). NCHR challenged the U.S. Interdiction-at-sea policy all the way to the Supreme Court, which unfortunately decided that the President had quasi-absolute powers outside of U.S. borders.
  It is important to note that for purposes of immigration enforcement, the U.S. border steadily receded from 12 miles to 3 miles (under Reagan), from 3 miles to sure footing on land (under Clinton), whereas a slot machine or a detainee in GTMO is not in US territory unless in the 12-mile limit. Note also that Customs and Border Patrol has a 100-mile wide authority to patrol on each side of the border, i.e. for purposes of immigration enforcement. All of New York City (its 8 million + residents) is within the border.
  In short, NCHR's legalization and immigration efforts, activities, and programs may have shifted focus and administrative and programmatic location over the years, but they always were part of NCHR's DNA. [source: Jocelyn "Juny" McCalla]
  - CAP, 1994-1998, undated; 5; 1 boxes
    - CAP - Community Action Program, 1994 (Box 31)
    - CAP - Geraldine Mehu, 1994-1995 (Box 31)
    - CAP - goals, 1995 (Box 31)
    - CAP - in rebellion with a proposed immigration bill, 1995 (Box 31)
    - CAP - focus groups, c. 1995 (Box 31)
    - CAP - Ford Foundation, 1995-1996 (Box 31)
    - CAP - resource and school board elections, 1996 (Box 31)
    - CAP - school board elections, 1996 (Box 31)
    - CAP - survey, 1996 (Box 31)
    - CAP - meeting, 1997 (Box 31)
    - CAP - fundraising, 1998 (Box 31)
    - CAP - Immigration Campaign, undated (Box 31)
  - HACAN, 1994-1997, undated; 6
    - HACAN - Haitian American Community Network, 1994 (Box 31)
    - HACAN - Network Fundraising Committee, 1997 (Box 31)
    - HACAN - "The Haitian American Community Action Network", undated (Box 31)
    - HACAN - meetings, undated (Box 31)
    - HACAN - Town Hall meeting, undated (Box 31)
  - HELCEP, 2004, undated; 7
    - HELCEP - First Quarter Report, 2004 (Box 31)
    - HELCEP - Progress Reports for 2002-2004 (Box 31)
    - HELCEP - Second Quarter Report, 2004 (Box 31)
    - HELCEP - project, undated (Box 31)
  - Immigration Project, 1992-2001; 8
    - Immigration Project - Asylum Study Project, 1992 (Box 31)
    - Immigration Project - National Asylum Study Project 2nd Quarter Report, 1992 (Box 31)
    - Immigration Project - Citizenship Campaign, 1997 (Box 31)
    - Immigration Project - NCHR - Citizenship Workshops and Training, 1998 (Box 31)
    - Immigration Project - Legal Referral/Information, 2001 (Box 31)
  - LEAP, 1997-2002, undated; 9
    - LEAP - Legal education and assistance project, 1997-2000 (Box 31)
    - LEAP - NYPD - Police Brutality, 1997-1999 (Box 31)
    - LEAP - Plans Projects, 1998-2001 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - Case Worker position, 1999 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - Program notes - research - planning documents, 1999-2000 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - Advisory Board Amendments, 2000 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - Advisory Committee, 2000 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - articles (civil rights + police brutality in Haiti), 2000 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - CAP Community Action Program - Federal Assistance Application, 2000 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - Chief Joseph Fox, 2000 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - civil rights in NYC, 2000 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - communication materials and contact us, 2000 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - Confirmation Letters, 2000 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - Conflict Resolution, 2000 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - Correspondence re: HALEFO - ORR, 2000 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - Domestic Violence, 2000 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - Focus Group 1 - training manual, 2000 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - Focus Groups, 2000 (Box 32)
    - LEAP - Focus Groups, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Forum Group - Notes, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Intake forms, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Interview Letter, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Interviews, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Legal Education + Assistance Project Building Police - Community Relations in New York proposal, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Legal Resource Pamphlet, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Literature Review, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Miscellaneous notes and Correspondence, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Policy Link, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Progress Reports, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Recent Developments in LEAP Interviews, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Referral list - Quality check (Results), 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - report, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Report Diagnostic, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Report Update/Focus Groups, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - Reports - updates - correspondence, 2000 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - research + reports, 2000; 1 of 2 (Box 33)
    - LEAP - research + reports, 2000; 2 of 2 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Research - Focus Groups, 2000 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Resources, 2000 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Semi Annual Progress Report, 2000 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Survey, 2000 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Work Plan, 2000 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Workshop notes, 2000 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Workshops, 2000 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Workshops, 2000 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Constitutional Rights, 2000 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Domestic Violence, c. 2000 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Flyer, c. 2000 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Intake forms, c. 2000 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Interview Questionnaire, c. 2000 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - 67th Precinct Community Council, 2000-2001 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - outreach to community leaders, 2000-2001 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Workshop (confirmations - accomplishments), 2000-2001 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Contacts, 2001 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - Interviews - Research - Reports, 2001 (Box 34)
    - LEAP - New York Foundation proposal, 2001 (Box 35)
    - LEAP - Quarterly Report, 2001 (Box 35)
    - LEAP - Report on Haitian Perspectives on NYPD, 2001 (Box 35)
    - LEAP - Workshop attendance, 2001 (Box 35)
    - LEAP - Budget, 2002 (Box 35)
    - LEAP - communication materials, undated (Box 35)
    - LEAP - diagnostic report, undated (Box 35)
    - LEAP - NCHR Legal Education and Assistance Project, undated (Box 35)
    - LEAP - Pamphlets/PR, undated (Box 35)
    - LEAP - Sa pou w fè si lapolis di w kanpe, undated (Box 35)
      (Kreyol)
    - LEAP - Workshop Contact Information, undated (Box 35)
    - LEAP - interviews - focus groups - notes, undated (Box 35)
  - Legalization Program, 1987-1989; 10
    - NCHR/LIRS Overview of Program Accomplishments, 1986-1988 (Box 35)
    - NCHR Adjustment/Legalization Program Progress Report, 1987 (Box 35)
    - NCHR Haitian Adjustment/Legalization Training Module, 1987 (Box 35)
    - NCHR Legalization Campaign Documents, 1987 (Box 35)
    - NCHR Legalization Outreach Documents, 1987 (Box 35)
    - Haitian and Cuban Refugee Adjustment Program, 1988 (Box 35)
    - Memo About NCHR Adjusutment/Legalization Program, 1988 (Box 35)
    - Legalization Outreach Project Documents, 1988-1989 (Box 35)
  - Restavek, 1999-2002, undated; 11
    - Restavek - campaign, 1999 (Box 35)
    - Restavek - event, 1999 (Box 35)
    - Restavek - Gala, 1999 (Box 35)
    - Restavek - photos, 1999 (Box 35)
    - Restavek - pre-benefit event, 1999 (Box 35)
    - Restavek - Human trafficking, 2002 (Box 35)
    - Restavek - Planning, 2003 (Box 35)
      (French)
    - Restavek - Training, 2003 (Box 35)
    - Restavek - Weekly and Quarterly Reports, 2003 (Box 35)
    - Restavek - Pamphlet, undated (Box 35)
    - Restavek - report comments, undated (Box 35)
  - Other Programs and Projects, 1982-2005, undated; 12
    - Department of State Agency for Int'l Dev., Haiti Project Paper, Legal Assistance to the Poor, 1982 (Box 35)
    - NCHR - LIRS Haitian research + advocacy project, 1986-1990, 1994 (Box 35)
    - NCHR Files From Henri-Robert Dubois on Haitian Farmworkers in Delaware-Virginia-Maryland, 1987 (Box 36)
    - Literacy project, Haiti, 1988 (Box 36)
    - AmFar International Aid Fund, Preliminary 1990 Program Prospectus, 1989 (Box 36)
    - Haitian Lawyers Committee Grant Proposal to Ford Foundation, 1989 (Box 36)
    - NCHR Draft Proposal for Program Projects, 1989-1990 (Box 36)
    - NCHR programs, 1991 (Box 36)
    - Temporary Protected Status campaign to legislators, 1991-1992; 1 of 2 (Box 36)
    - Temporary Protected Status campaign to legislators, 1991-1992; 2 of 2 (Box 36)
    - Temporary Protocted Status Campaign to legislators, 1991-1992; 3 of 3 (Box 36)
    - Bush Policy US Coast Guard Haitian Refugees, 1992 (Box 36)
    - Community development agency- NY, 1992 (Box 36)
    - Economic and Social Council, 1992 (Box 36)
    - Haitian refugees advocacy, 1992 (Box 36)
    - Cooperation with the Haitian government on refugees, 1993 (Box 36)
    - Outreach to community leaders, 1993 (Box 37)
    - US Refugee Policy, 1993 (Box 37)
    - US Coast Guard Haitian deportation, 1993-1994 (Box 37)
    - Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corp., 1994 (Box 37)
    - Fund for New Priorities, 1994 (Box 37)
    - Letter to NHRF re: human rights task force in Haiti, 1994 (Box 37)
    - National immigration forum, 1994 (Box 37)
    - NYANA Project Strive, 1994 (Box 37)
    - The Future Asylum Program, 1994 (Box 37)
    - Bahamas repatriation policy, 1995 (Box 37)
    - Caribbean human rights network, 1995 (Box 37)
    - Haiti programs, 1995 (Box 37)
    - Haiti visit, 1995 (Box 37)
    - Holland, James + proposal for NCHR's membership program, 1995 (Box 37)
    - Lutheran World Relief Haiti, 1995 (Box 37)
    - NCHR archives in Haiti, 1995 (Box 37)
    - NCHR Community Action plans, 1995 (Box 37)
    - Presidential Commission on Student Scholarship, 1995 (Box 37)
    - NCHR Caribbean Migration Project, memos + reports, 1995-1996 (Box 37)
    - Senate immigration bill, 1995-1996 (Box 37)
    - Unity and empowerment conference, 1995-1996 (Box 37)
    - Bios, info, summaries of panelists, 1996 (Box 37)
    - Caribbean Migration + Human Rights project, 1996 (Box 38)
    - Documents on income from conference, 1996 (Box 38)
    - Haiti Office, 1996 (Box 38)
    - Haitian Police Training, 1996 (Box 38)
    - Immigration advocacy, 1996 (Box 38)
    - Logistics committee notes and minutes, 1996 (Box 38)
    - NCHR Caribbean migration and human rights project, 1996 (Box 38)
    - NCHR migration projects, 1996 (Box 38)
    - NCHR surveys, 1996 (Box 38)
    - Outreach committee, 1996 (Box 38)
    - Press releases on Haitian refugees, 1996 (Box 38)
    - Program Committee notes and minutes, 1996 (Box 38)
    - Unaccompanied Haitian minors, 1996 (Box 38)
    - Community development resource guide, c. 1996 (Box 38)
    - Drafts of report on migration issues, 1997; 1 of 3 (Box 38)
    - Drafts of report on migration issues, 1997; 2 of 3 (Box 38)
    - Drafts of report on migration issues, 1997; 3 of 3 (Box 38)
    - New York Community Trust, 1997 (Box 39)
    - Ministière de la Justice, Ecole de la Magistrature, Programme de Formation des Magistrats, 1997-1998 (Box 39)
    - From Haitian slave-child to middle-class American, 1998 (Box 39)
    - Haiti Police Reform, 1998 (Box 39)
    - Humanitarianism + War Project NGO Policy Dialogue, 1998 (Box 39)
    - Institutionalizing Human Rights in Haiti, 1998 (Box 39)
    - Media archive proposal + bulletins, 1999 (Box 39)
    - Monitoring report of Community + Family Strengthening - Integration Program + Ethnic National Program, 1999 (Box 39)
    - NCHR's Human Rights Program, 1999 (Box 39)
    - Articles (civil rights + Haitian police), 2000 (Box 39)
    - Auguste Tavernier, 2000 (Box 39)
    - Bar Association - Referral, 2000 (Box 39)
    - CLE/Law related conference or forum material, 2000 (Box 39)
    - Creole vocabulary, 2000 (Box 39)
    - NCHR Major Activities and Accomplishments, 2001-2002 (Box 39)
    - Fund for New Citizens grant letter, 2003 (Box 39)
    - NCHR- Haitians Stepping Forward Together in 2004 (Box 39)
    - NCHR Stepping Forward Together in 2004 GOTV Campaign (Box 39)
    - NYIC poll workers, 2004 (Box 39)
    - NYU- Center for Problem Solving, 2004 (Box 39)
    - Grow Haiti: Developing the processes to rebuild Haitian Communities, pilot program proposal to Develop the Roadmap, 2005 (Box 39)
    - Community abroad Miami, undated (Box 39)
    - Global Exchange Emergency Campaign to Restore Democracy in Haiti, undated (Box 39)
    - GOTV phone call packet, undated (Box 39)
    - Human Rights Education + Legal Assistance Project, a proposal on behalf of the Haitian Center for the Defense of Civil Liberties, by Jean-Jacques Honorat, Exec. Dir., undated (Box 39)
    - Law first Pro Bono - Referral, undated (Box 39)
    - Legal Organization and Services referral list, undated (Box 39)
    - Legal Referral List, undated (Box 39)
    - NCHR program plans post 1994, undated (Box 39)
    - Precinct maps + contact persons in NYC, undated (Box 39)
    - The Refugee Advocacy Project, undated (Box 39)
- Legal, 1980-2007, undated; 3; 25 boxes
  The Legal series contains files related to NCHR's work on broad legal cases effecting US immigration policy and human rights accountability in Haiti, as well as legal support NCHR provided to individuals, largely related to immigration and asylum in the US.
  The Series is arranged into four subseries. The Haitian Government Cases subseries documents NCHR's and its partners' legal efforts around accountability, reparations, and truth-seeking in Haiti. The Individual Cases subseries contains material related to NCHR's legal advocacy on behalf of individuals, largely around immigration/asylum issues in the US, and human rights and civil rights violations in Haiti. The Haitian Centers Council vs. McNary subseries contains documents related to this seminal 1992 case that sought to gain access for legal advocacy and representation purposes to Haitian immigrants being held at the US Naval Base in Guantanamo Bay and on board US Coast Guard vessals, and to bar the US Coast Guard from repatriating "screened" refugees. Finally, the Other Legal Materials subseries documents various legal projects largely relating to immigration and asylum.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access to the Individual Cases subseries is restricted. Collection contains potentially sensitive information. Contact Research Services for Access.
  - Haitian Government Cases, 1983-2005; 13; 4 boxes
    - "Interdictions Log Political Section U.S. Embassy, 1983 (Box 40)
    - "Truths and Revelations" Broken Silence Prosper Avril, 1991 (Box 40)
    - Affidavit transfers by the Duvalier family, 1986 (Box 40)
    - Affidavit: diversion of National funds from Public Treasury, undated (Box 40)
    - Avril case notes, 1991 (Box 40)
    - Avril immunity letter, 1991 (Box 40)
    - Avril lawsuit complaint, 1991 (Box 40)
    - Avril lawsuit- complaint, 1991 (Box 40)
    - Avril lawsuit notes, 1991 (Box 40)
    - Avril lawsuit press releases, 1991 (Box 40)
    - Avril's case- affidavits, 1994 (Box 40)
    - Belance v. Front Pour L'avancement et le Progres Haitien (FRAPH), 1994 (Box 40)
    - Complaint beore the Inter-American Comission of Human Rights, 1994 (Box 40)
    - Correspondence about lawsuit against Prosper Avril, 1990 (Box 40)
    - Duvalier court case, 1987 (Box 40)
    - Haiti against Duvalier et al. lawsuit, 1986 (Box 40)
    - Haiti v. Aurore Ligonde, 1984 (Box 40)
    - Haiti v. Duvalier et al. lawsuit, 1986; 1 of 2 (Box 40)
    - Haiti v. Duvalier et al. lawsuit, 1986; 2 of 2 (Box 40)
    - Haiti v. Duvalier trial case, 1987 (Box 41)
    - Haiti v. Michele Bennett Duvalier Lawsuit, 1986 (Box 41)
    - Haiti v. Sambour, 1986 (Box 41)
    - Haitians v. US Law, 1994 (Box 41)
    - Inter-American Commission on Human Rights, 2000; 1 of 2 (Box 41)
      [Spanish]
    - Inter-American Commission on Human Rights, 2000; 2 of 2 (Box 41)
    - International Human Rights Clinic - Petitioners Report, 2001 (Box 41)
    - Jean-Juste vs. Duvalier and Haiti vs. Sambour lawsuits, 1986 (Box 41)
    - Jean-Juste vs. Duvalier judgment, 1988 (Box 41)
    - Jean-Juste vs. Duvalier proposal final judgment, 1987 (Box 41)
    - Lawsuits and Human Rights after the end of Duvalier government [h], 1986-1987 (Box 41)
    - Master Exhibit Haitian Asylum Cases, 1983 (Box 64)
    - Notice to wave immunity to Avril, 1991 (Box 41)
    - Overthrowing of Avril, 1990 (Box 41)
    - Paul v. Avril - motion to dismiss, 1991 (Box 41)
    - Paul v. Avril complaint for torture, 1991 (Box 41)
    - Recovery of Duvalier assets, 1986 (Box 42)
    - Request of assistance for Haiti vs. Duvalier lawsuit, 1987 (Box 42)
    - Testimonies of St. Fleur (Justice Secretary) and Delagaer (Finance Secretary) for the Haiti v. Duvalier trial, 1987 (Box 42)
    - Testimony of Andre Beaupian (accountant) in the Haiti vs. Duvalier trial case, 1987 (Box 42)
    - Testimony of Gaston (bank director) on thefts during Duvalier, 1987 (Box 42)
    - Testimony of McCalla in Haiti v. Michele Benett Duvalier, 1991 (Box 42)
    - U.S. Navy and Marine Corps Correspondence with Phillipe Louis-Jean, 2004-2005 (Box 42)
    - Various testimonies of public agencies in the Haiti vs. Duvalier trial [h], 1987 (Box 42)
  - Individual Cases, 1980-2007; 14; 8 boxes
    Materials in the Individual Cases subseries contain potentially sensitive information and are closed to use.
  - Haitian Centers Council v. McNary, 1984-1994; 15; 8 boxes
    - "16 Haitians Slain in Week of Strife", 1992 (Box 49)
    - "UN Officials Rebuke US on Haitians", 1992 (Box 49)
    - "What's Happening" newsletter, 1992 (Box 49)
    - "What's Happening" newsletter, 1992 (Box 49)
    - AFF affidavit, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affidavit of Andy Kershaw, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affidavit of Andy Kershaw, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affidavit of Antoine Eustache, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affidavit of Antoine Eustache, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affidavit of Jennie Smith, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affidavit of Jennie Smith, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affidavit of John Brittain, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affidavit of John Brittain, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affidavit of Linda Diebel, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affidavit of William G. O'Neill, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affirmation of Carolyn P. Blum, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affirmation of Carroll L. Lucht, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affirmation of Graham Boyd, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affirmation of Graham Boyd, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Affirmation of Milot Baptiste, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Amicus brief (Yale), 1992 (Box 49)
    - Amicus briefs and Appellees' brief, 1992 (Box 49)
    - Amnesty International memos, 1992 (Box 50)
    - Appeal against McNary, 1991 (Box 50)
    - Appeal against McNary, 1992 (Box 50)
    - Appeal against McNary, 1992 (Box 50)
    - Appeal against McNary, 1992 (Box 50)
    - Appeal against McNary, 1992 (Box 50)
    - Appeals from the Southern District of Florida, 1992 (Box 50)
    - Brief of Amici Curiae Haitian Service Organization, 1992 (Box 50)
    - Brief of Amici Curiae in support of Plaintiffs, 1992 (Box 50)
    - Brief of Amici Curiae Office of UN High Commissioner for Refugees, 1992 (Box 50)
    - Brief of Amici Curiae the Lawyers Committee for Human Rights in support of plaintiffs, 1992 (Box 50)
    - Brief of Amicus Curae Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, 1992; 1 of 2 (Box 50)
    - Brief of Amicus Curae Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, 1992; 2 of 2 (Box 51)
    - Brief of amicus curiae- International Human Rights Law Group, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Brief of amicus curiae NAACP in support of plaintiffs, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Brief of Appellees, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Death list- read 12/15/1991 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of Elliot J. Schrage, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of Elliot J. Schrage, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of Enos Ned Banda, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of Enos Ned Banda, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of James A. Rogers, 1991 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of James A. Rogers, 1991 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of John W. Cummings, 1992; 1 of 2 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of John W. Cummings, 1992; 2 of 2 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of Martin Chery, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of Robert Rubin, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of Ronald Auburg, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of Wells C. Klein, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of Wells C. Klein, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of William O'Neill, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Declaration of Wynn Phillips and Rae A. Brough, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Declarations of Wynn Phillips and Rae A. Brough, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Deposition of Brunson McKinley, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Deposition of Grover Joseph Rees III, 1992 (Box 52)
    - Deposition of Irma Rios, 1989; 1 of 2 (Box 52)
    - Deposition of Irma Rios, 1989; 2 of 2 (Box 52)
    - Deposition of Joseph F. Becelia, 1992 (Box 52)
    - Deposition of Leon C. Jennings, 1992 (Box 52)
    - Deposition of Manuel Bojorquez, 1992; 1 of 2 (Box 52)
    - Deposition of Manuel Bojorquez, 1992; 2 of 2 (Box 52)
    - Deposition of Robert S. Gelard, 1992; 1 of 2 (Box 52)
    - Deposition of Robert S. Gelard, 1992; 2 of 2 (Box 52)
    - Depositions of Gunther Wagner and James J. McClain, 1992; 1 of 2 (Box 52)
    - Depositions of Gunther Wagner and James J. McClain, 1992; 2 of 2 (Box 52)
    - Draft of Nature of the Action, 1994 (Box 52)
    - Exhibitions in case, 1992 (Box 53)
    - Groups targeted by persecution, 1992 (Box 53)
    - Haitian briefing, 1992 (Box 53)
    - HCC v. McNary, 1992 (Box 53)
    - Index of Exhibits, 1992 (Box 53)
    - Letter from Michael Singer to Robert E. Juceam, 1992 (Box 53)
    - Letter to Donna Hrinak- witness, 1992; 1 of 2 (Box 53)
    - Letter to Donna Hrinak- witness, 1992; 2 of 2 (Box 53)
    - Letter to Gregg A. Beyer- witness, 1992 (Box 53)
    - Letter to Judge Sterling Johnson Jr., 1992 (Box 53)
    - Letter to Michael Jay Singer to Robert Juceam, 1992 (Box 53)
    - Letter to the press, 1992 (Box 53)
    - Letters to Judge Sterling Johnson, 1992 (Box 53)
    - List of Haitian migrants for repatriation, 1992 (Box 53)
    - List of Haitian refugees who refuse to take second test, 1992 (Box 53)
    - Memo from Haitian Parliament to the President, 1991 (Box 53)
    - Memo in support of motion for Class Action Certification, 1991 (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous letters, 1992 (Box 53)
    - Motion for class action certification, 1991 (Box 53)
    - Motion for sanctions, 1992 (Box 53)